hey guys I saw this the other day
someone wrote I've never seen this
problem before it looks interesting
enough so let's do it if you want to try
this on your own pause it right now
because I'm going to solve it in three
two one so this one is not super
difficult I think they're expecting
people to see the right triangles here
connect these and think a squared plus b
squared equals c squared and then do the
same thing here same thing here and then
maybe they expect you to connect this
and think what am I supposed to do with
this shape it can be very confusing if
you go down this route but the simple
way to do it is just to complete this
right triangle this side right here the
height of this triangle is going to be 2
plus 2 plus 2 which is six and the base
is going to be four plus two plus two
which is eight and if we call this last
side C we can do the Pythagorean theorem
we're going to plug in 6 for the a 8 for
the B and then solve for C 6 squared is
36 plus 8 squared is 64 and that's all
going to equal c squared 36 plus 64 is
equal to 100 and after we square root
both sides we get C is equal to 10 and
that's this one right here how exciting